mhric.org 2017-02-26

# Your Privacy

### Introduction

Thank you for visiting the Mid-Hudson Regional Information Center's (the "MHRIC") website. This website is designed to make it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with the MHRIC. The MHRIC recognizes that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit the MHRIC's website.

Consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law, this policy describes the MHRIC's privacy practices regarding information collected from users of this website. This policy describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy only applies to this website, you should examine the privacy policy of any website, including other State agency websites, that you access via the MHRIC's website.

For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person, as opposed to a corporate entity, which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. The MHRIC only collects personal information when that information is provided voluntarily by sending an e-mail, responding to a survey, or completing an on-line transaction.

###  **Information Collected Automatically When You Visit this website**

When visiting this website the MHRIC automatically collects and stores some information about your visit, however; none of this information is personal information.

The information that is collected automatically is used to improve this website's content and to help the MHRIC understand how users are interacting with the website. This information is collected for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and least interest to our constituents, and to improve the utility of the material available on the website. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and the MHRIC is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from the website for commercial marketing purposes.

###  Cookies

The MHRIC may use a technology called "cookies" which can be used to provide tailored information from a website in order to better serve you. A cookie is an element of data that is sent to your browser and stored on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. Refusing or deleting cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this website.

The cookies the MHRIC uses do not obtain personal information about website visitors. The only way we can obtain personal information is if you voluntarily provide it.

###  Information Collected When You E-mail this website or Initiate an Online Transaction

During your visit to this website you may send an e-mail to the MHRIC Webmaster. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website, or to forward your message to another State agency for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and the MHRIC is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.

During your visit to this website you may initiate a transaction such as a survey, registration, order form for publications, or you may submit forms for inclusion in one of the MHRIC's electronic systems. The information, including personal information, volunteered by you in initiating the transaction is used by the MHRIC to operate MHRIC programs, which include the provision of goods, services, information, and the adjudication of awards. All information provided to the MHRIC, through any media, will be kept private and will not be disclosed except as provided under section 110-a of the Workers' Compensation Law, and Articles 6 and 6-A of the Public Officers Law.

The MHRIC does not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this website. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail or through an online transaction will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access. The MHRIC strongly encourages parents and teachers to be involved in children's Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online.

###  Information and Choice

As noted above, the MHRIC does not collect any personal information about you during your visit to this website unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or initiating an online transaction. You may choose not to send us an e-mail, or submit information via this website. This will not prevent you from requesting services or products from the MHRIC by other means and will not normally have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other features of the website, including browsing or downloading most publicly available information.

###  Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website

The collection of information through this website and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Personal Privacy Protection Law, the Freedom of Information Law and Workers' Compensation Law §110-a Confidentiality of Workers' Compensation Records. Participation in an online transaction resulting in the disclosure of personal information to the MHRIC by the constituent, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by the MHRIC for the purposes reasonably ascertainable from the nature and terms of the transaction.

The MHRIC may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce the MHRIC's rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to the MHRIC's information technology assets or against other inappropriate use of this website.

The MHRIC is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through this website against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Consequently, the MHRIC limits employee access to personal information collected through this website to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information are required to follow the law and MHRIC procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.

In addition, the MHRIC has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this website as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of the website for all users, the MHRIC employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this website.

### Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through this website. 

###  Links

In order to provide users with certain information, the MHRIC provides links to the websites of local, state, and federal government agencies, and to the websites of other organizations. A link does not constitute an endorsement of the content, viewpoint, accuracy, opinions, policies, products, services, or accessibility of that website. Once you link to another website from this website, including one maintained by the state, you are subject to the terms and conditions of that website, including, but not limited to, its Internet privacy policy.
